[{"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338922", "question": "What device does Harry Potter use to track the comings and goings of people at Hogwarts castle?", "answer": "The Marauder's Map", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c15f", "question": "Fax is short for which word?", "answer": "Facsimile", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b12c", "question": "Which Egyptian queen was married to pharaoh Akhenaten?", "answer": "Nefertiti", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6007823abd51d85e222ab655", "question": "How did the Mus\u00e9e Picasso in Paris come to own its collection of Picasso's works?", "answer": "Since he left no will, his\u00a0death duties\u00a0to the French state were paid in the form of works from his personal collection.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d7af2596a59cbdfbd3b9", "question": "Who is credited with the legend of the Lost City of Atlantis?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600b87961d8c1817608d53e9", "question": "Which U.S. monument has a smaller replica hidden in a nearby manhole?", "answer": "Washington Monument  (\"Bench Mark A,\u201d a 12-foot replica of the monument, is a Geodetic Control Point used by surveyors.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b70b06d333868d34d6f7", "question": "Refugees on which ship were refused entry to both Cuba and the U.S. in 1939?", "answer": "St. Louis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febbc8b7e83c707845b214d", "question": "In what round of the NFL draft was quarterback Tom Brady selected in?", "answer": "Brady was the 199th pick in the sixth round of the 2000 NFL draft.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc0a8ec223966ae8f885d", "question": "What guards the Ark of the Covenant in \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c039", "question": "Soteriophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dependence on others", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a820", "question": "What river forms much of the border between Washington and Oregon?", "answer": "Columbia River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "591c37a4815febcc896f9272", "question": "What Turkish city has spread to both sides of the Bosphorus Strait?", "answer": "Istanbul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede5ed6ce05a3942286df3", "question": "The \"Australian Open\" is a Grand Slam tournament in which sport?", "answer": "Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8b", "question": "What Oliver Stone movie features the characters Mickey and Mallory?", "answer": "Natural Born Killers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cb7e877e98cb97778a1c", "question": "Which country's Easter brunch typically includes a ryemeal soup known as zurek?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f1", "question": "In what movie does Steve Martin play the character of Navin Johnson?", "answer": "The Jerk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a62972ebb971c1417fb90", "question": "What fish was the subject of a dispute between Spain and Canada from 1994 to 1996?", "answer": "Turbot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feba9067e83c707845b20d0", "question": "A computer opponent's ability to adaptively challenge a player is known as what?", "answer": "Artificial intelligence (AI)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b512", "question": "What is the other name for the card game Patience?", "answer": "Solitaire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c6", "question": "Which \"Simpsons\" character has a doctorate in Computer Science?", "answer": "Apu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea77bfff048f679a45abce", "question": "Meningitis is characterized by what major symptoms?", "answer": "Stiff neck, sudden high fever and a severe headache", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339076", "question": "Nut, or Neuth, was the Egyptian goddess of what?", "answer": "Sky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca98", "question": "What is the technical term for the voice box found in mammals?", "answer": "Larynx", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a7cf20565ad31a57c7ef", "question": "What was the first US state to pass a law requiring mandatory seat belt use?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b141", "question": "Who did Bill Clinton defeat in the 1996 US Presidential election?", "answer": "Bob Dole", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f22", "question": "What TV show closes with a logo for \"30th Century Fox\"?", "answer": "Futurama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339274", "question": "What is the fairy tale equivalent of Augustus in the show \"Once Upon A Time\"?", "answer": "Pinocchio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b780", "question": "What city's Summer Olympics had the beaver Amik as their mascot?", "answer": "Montreal's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c076", "question": "How many children did Noah have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e84", "question": "What power does \"The Monkey's Paw\" possess in the 1902 short story?", "answer": "It grants three wishes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4d979d08b8581f80b092aa", "question": "What name was given to the tropical cyclone that destroyed large parts of the Houston metropolitan area in the United States in August of 2017?", "answer": "Hurricane Harvey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d8", "question": "White creme de menthe is added to what alcohol to make a Stinger cocktail?", "answer": "Cognac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aafa", "question": "Which country borders Chad to the north?", "answer": "Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5de655fff89b9ec3da2d335c", "question": "What auto company made the \"flathead\" V8 engine, which was the first affordable mass market V8?", "answer": "Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338990", "question": "What Beatrix Potter character has roasted grasshopper for supper after failing to catch minnows?", "answer": "Mr. Jeremy Fisher", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "596371ad967692ea851899bb", "question": "What country music singer was born in Muskogee, Oklahoma in 1983?", "answer": "Carrie Underwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb0", "question": "What relation to you is your uncle's father?", "answer": "Grandfather", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc79", "question": "What company's famous plaid pattern is called \"novacheck\"?", "answer": "Burberry's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b2a", "question": "Who was the Roman demigod best known for his strength?", "answer": "Hercules", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e024fe83fe1f2a824b87", "question": "Who organized the famous \"March of the Mill Children\" from Philadelphia to President Theodore Roosevelt's summer home in 1903?", "answer": "Mary Harris Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e1", "question": "What does FIFA stand for?", "answer": "F\u00e9d\u00e9ration Internationale de Football Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7e", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Dill in the novel \"To Kill a Mockingbird\"?", "answer": "Truman Capote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b8d4d22b42d4a3561a9efc", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", which employee of Mrs. Parker was framed with stealing $850,000 from Senator Chalmers?", "answer": "Samantha", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cae4", "question": "What current-day country was writer, neurologist and psychiatrist Viktor Frankl born in?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbff36ce05a3942286f07", "question": "Which two popular actors starred in the lead roles in the film \"Rounders\"?", "answer": "Matt Damon and Edward Norton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9033701dd7bf43be5e86f", "question": "Where was Heineken beer first made?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e9a", "question": "What movie did the villain Dr. Szell appear in?", "answer": "Marathon Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab7e", "question": "Sierra Leone is located on which African coast?", "answer": "West", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adab", "question": "The \"Harappan Civilization\" is also known by what other name?", "answer": "Indus Valley Civilization", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cd7e7e347d002c297e4c5", "question": "What is the largest country wholly within Europe?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a25f1e16682715b82711ce4", "question": "What is the name of the strait located between the Italy and Albania?", "answer": "Straits of Otranto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5cc", "question": "What is the name given to the largest number ever used in a mathematical proof?", "answer": "Graham's Number", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a677", "question": "Which US state was named after the King of France?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918a", "question": "How many keys does a baby grand piano have?", "answer": "88", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58bb33a5e368446ca7bd6847", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion in search of?", "answer": "Courage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ed", "question": "In popular literature, what is Princess Aurora's better-known name?", "answer": "Sleeping Beauty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339583", "question": "Who played the Captain of the fishing boat in the movie \"The Perfect Storm\"?", "answer": "George Clooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b8", "question": "Zion National Park is located in which US state?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f7", "question": "What US president was fatally shot in 1881?", "answer": "James Garfield", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cb70de5f96e155acab35d35", "question": "What two boxers fought in the famous match-up dubbed the \"Thrilla in Manila\"?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali and Joe Frazier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133960a", "question": "Who directed the 1994 movie \"True Lies\"?", "answer": "James Cameron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b74e", "question": "What is the highest number on a standard roulette wheel?", "answer": "36", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af89", "question": "Who was the second president of the US?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a7", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f95", "question": "Which word describing chaos first appeared in Milton's \"Paradise Lost\"?", "answer": "Pandemonium", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd7", "question": "What film introduced the fraternity Lambda Lambda Lambda?", "answer": "Revenge of the Nerds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c72", "question": "What TV show features the fictional TV show \"Tool Time\"?", "answer": "Home Improvement", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a84", "question": "What 1974 horror film's title weapon was a Poulan 245A?", "answer": "The Texas Chainsaw Massacre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f1a7cee580c7f8fd1e51", "question": "Who said, \"You only live once, but if you do it right, once is good enough.\"?", "answer": "Mae West", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590498aecf93664eb1048689", "question": "A statue of Lady Godiva stands in the centre which English city?", "answer": "Coventry", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa2f", "question": "Christmas Island is a territory belonging to which country?", "answer": "Australia\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e2", "question": "What image appears on The Saint's business card?", "answer": "A stick figure with a halo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca7", "question": "In Marvel Comics, Steve Rogers was given a super-soldier serum and a shield, becoming what superhero?", "answer": "Captain America", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5971df1189261e916c8e09a6", "question": "What is the name of Batman's Butler?", "answer": "Alfred", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b795", "question": "Christmas caroling began as what old English custom?", "answer": "Wassailing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339992", "question": "How many episodes of \"The Cosby Show\" were made?", "answer": "197", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e95", "question": "What movie did the villain Amon Goeth appear in?", "answer": "Schindler's List", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390dc", "question": "Who was the author of the novel \"The Midwich Cuckoos\"?", "answer": "John Wyndham", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c66c", "question": "In 1976, Viking 1 made history after it landed where?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a24", "question": "Who aimed his \"Emporio\" clothing line at younger buyers?", "answer": "Giorgio Armani", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a716", "question": "Lake of the Ozarks is located in which US state?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59da1af6f6756c9b30ba14f4", "question": "In which film did a Rolls Royce have the number plate AU1?", "answer": "Goldfinger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02e", "question": "What decade saw the introduction of the Easy\u00adBake Oven, Lite Brite, and Spirograph?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac24", "question": "Which country borders Suriname to the south?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a76", "question": "On \"Sesame Street\", which two characters live in an apartment at 123 Sesame Street?", "answer": "Bert and Ernie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a06", "question": "What D.H. Lawrence novel was originally titled \"Tenderness\"?", "answer": "Lady Chatterley's Lover", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133993b", "question": "What character on the original Star Trek TV series was played by James Doohan?", "answer": "Scotty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339597", "question": "Musical duo Kaoma introduced the world to which dance in 1989?", "answer": "Lambada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e2a7fe83fe1f2a824ba1", "question": "What Japanese action created tension with the United States?", "answer": "Japan's seizure of territory in China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb03", "question": "What magazine publisher founded a motorcycle club called the \"Capitalist Tools\"?", "answer": "Malcolm Forbes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b0", "question": "Most of Transylvania is now part of what modern-day country?", "answer": "Romania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdad", "question": "What food item shares its name with Brad and Janet's hospitable host in \"The Rocky Horror Picture Show\"?", "answer": "A frankfurter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b505", "question": "What two skills make up the winter biathlon?", "answer": "Cross-country skiing and target shooting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad87", "question": "Who proposed the idea of \"Laissez-faire\"?", "answer": "Adam Smith", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecd1e4ec223966ae8f88c1", "question": "While filming \"Guardians of the Galaxy\", what did director James Gunn give out as rewards to his actors and crew?", "answer": "Play-Doh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58a0f5ea732c90c4fd3069cf", "question": "Who was the childhood playmate of little Jackie Papers?", "answer": "Puff, the Magic Dragon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc61", "question": "The name \"denim\" originates from what European language?", "answer": "French", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d7", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Selma's Choice,\" Homer can't go to Duff Gardens because he's sick from eating what?", "answer": "An old, old sandwich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea785fff048f679a45abd9", "question": "What is the only mammal to have oval rather than circular blood corpuscles?", "answer": "Camel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6000ece89a72b906b34e3ce7", "question": "The only known monotremes in the animal kingdom are the echidna and which other creature?", "answer": "Platypus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c943877e98cb977789f2", "question": "Which European capital's harbor is called the Golden Horn?", "answer": "Istanbul's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc2", "question": "What fictitious murderer first appeared in the story \"String of Pearls: A Romance\"?", "answer": "Sweeny Todd", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cbd", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional \"The Raccoons\" fraternity?", "answer": "The Honeymooners", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ad", "question": "What former Cosby Show star tied the knot with Lenny Kravitz in 1987?", "answer": "Lisa Bonet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bd05aedce677f092a9a4018", "question": "In the book \"The Aspen Account\", who is revealed to be dead at the start?", "answer": "Kurt Matthews", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b8d4a72b42d4a3561a9efb", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what nickname did Katchoo go by when working in L.A. as an escort?", "answer": "Baby June", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c3", "question": "On what movie is the TV show \"Alice\" based?", "answer": "Alice Doesn't Live Here Anymore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beee", "question": "What are people encouraged to kiss under?", "answer": "Mistletoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c698", "question": "What constellation represents a hunter with a club and shield?", "answer": "Orion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a97820565ad31a57c804", "question": "Where is the \"grassy knoll\" located?", "answer": "Dealey Plaza, Dallas, Texas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a466", "question": "In what state would you find the Black Rock Desert?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af46", "question": "Who was the famous teacher of Socrates?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc1ed6ce05a3942286f18", "question": "What country is the setting for the film \"The Deep\"?", "answer": "Bermuda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c755", "question": "What is the opposite of insulin and secreted by the pancreas?", "answer": "Glucagon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6002436e4be4723ccac22196", "question": "In Jonathan Swift\u2019s \"Gulliver\u2019s Travels\", what is the name of the island inhabited by tiny people?", "answer": "Lilliput", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdd5de60499cffc60b84232", "question": "Which country is ruled by the Al Sabah dynasty?", "answer": "Kuwait", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e9adfe83fe1f2a824bea", "question": "What scientist challenged church dogma but was nevertheless buried in a Catholic cathedral in Frombork, Poland?", "answer": "Copernicus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b905", "question": "The delicacy known as fois gras traditionally comes from what part of the duck or goose?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfdbb9dc5ec6cd98a8325", "question": "What novel is set on a desert planet inhabited by giant sandworms?", "answer": "Dune", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be5", "question": "What year did Johnny Depp receive his Hollywood Walk of Fame star in?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a68d", "question": "What modern-day US state was inhabited by the Calusa Indians?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6bf", "question": "What acid gives vinegar its smell and taste?", "answer": "Acetic acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339175", "question": "Who voices Darth Vader in the original Star Wars movies?", "answer": "James Earl Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feddb0a6ce05a3942286d8d", "question": "What is the name of the famous Christmas Carol sung by Mariah Carey?", "answer": "\"All I Want for Christmas Is You\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef2", "question": "What TV title character has a rat named Steve McQueen?", "answer": "Dr. Gregory House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c44c", "question": "How many chromosomes does a goat have?", "answer": "60", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad6", "question": "In which continent would you find the Lena River?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "591c376d815febcc896f9270", "question": "What year did Dashiell Hammett publish the novel \"The Maltese Falcon\"?", "answer": "1929", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d8", "question": "Which year was the first Indiana Jones movie released?", "answer": "1981", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600b87f21d8c1817608d53ec", "question": "What was the name of British Prince Philip's mother?", "answer": "Princess Alice of Battenberg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1d", "question": "What was the scarecrow in \"The Wizard of Oz\" lacking?", "answer": "Brain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339405", "question": "Who narrated the 2007 movie \"Enchanted\"?", "answer": "Julie Andrews", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c476", "question": "What type of animal was the first ever to be cloned from an adult cell?", "answer": "A sheep", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8ac5601dd7bf43be5e76a", "question": "Which type of fruit juice did Dole sell first?", "answer": "Pineapple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b433", "question": "What year did the Mau Mau Uprising end?", "answer": "1960", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc5d", "question": "What popular architect designed the Guggenheim Museum of Modern Art?", "answer": "Frank Lloyd Wright", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c1", "question": "Which 1954 film won eight Oscars?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a96a", "question": "Gouda and Edam are cities in what country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b498e662d71a53650fec", "question": "Which author wrote the \"Winnie-the-Pooh\" books?", "answer": "A. A. Milne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede0b96ce05a3942286dba", "question": "Which Bavarian castle did Walt Disney sculpt Cinderella's after?", "answer": "Neuschwanstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf0", "question": "What European conflict lasted 116 years?", "answer": "The Hundred Years War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a728cc86bcd28c11938328c", "question": "Dover is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339223", "question": "What is the name of Futurama's first episode aired in 1999?", "answer": "Space Pilot 3000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f9bb01dd7bf43be5e84d", "question": "What was football legend Joe Namath's nickname?", "answer": "Broadway Joe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace6", "question": "Which country was former Prime Minister Tony Blair born in?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd03", "question": "It is sometimes considered a fashion faux pas to wear white after what holiday?", "answer": "Labor Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b358df35db0d66a186cb565", "question": "Burt Reynolds played the role of who on the TV show \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "Blacksmith Quint Asper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff1420ab0ee8c595b6d39aa", "question": "Who designed the logo for Old Dutch Cleanser?", "answer": "Georgia O'Keefe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a52", "question": "What TV family had three sons named Brad, Mark, and Randy?", "answer": "The Taylor's from Home Improvement", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69b9820565ad31a57c761", "question": "Jimmy Carter served in which military branch?", "answer": "U.S. Navy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7df", "question": "In which US state is Shenandoah National Park located?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f939fa5fdd6dd25324f5", "question": "What film did John Wayne win his only Oscar for?", "answer": "True Grit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ea", "question": "What type of snake is a Sidewinder?", "answer": "Rattlesnake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fc2f523cee580c7f8fd1e5a", "question": "What was the deadliest maritime disaster?", "answer": "MV Wilhelm Gustloff", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a4", "question": "How many bones are there in the human skull?", "answer": "22", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133896c", "question": "Who replaced Severus Snape as Potions Master at Hogwarts School?", "answer": "Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392c9", "question": "What 1987 song holds the record for the most MTV Video Music Awards with 9?", "answer": "\"Sledgehammer\" by Peter Gabriel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c266", "question": "How is the year 2000 written in Roman numerals?", "answer": "MM", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff214fe31a458464a93c45b", "question": "Who came up with \"The Allegory of the Cave\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a6", "question": "What is the axilla better known as?", "answer": "Armpit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b64f01dd7bf43be5e7d9", "question": "Which famous author worked as an entertainment director on a cruise line?", "answer": "J.D. Salinger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad7", "question": "What \"Saturday Night Live\" castmember played Sean Connery in their Celebrity Jeopardy skits?", "answer": "Darrell Hammond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe36ed40ada16518afdc046", "question": "What is the name of a popular Italian citrus and vanilla flavored liqueur?", "answer": "Tuaca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a91f", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Shafter?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00d", "question": "What was the real first name of David Soul's \"Hutch\" on \"Starsky and Hutch\"?", "answer": "Ken", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d08181a1c922dd1ac64bf", "question": "Ulaanbaatar is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Mongolia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c210", "question": "When were the first Winter Olympic Games held?", "answer": "1924", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c88e61b22f44c2d77a29c3f", "question": "What is Patty's last name in the 1978 film \"Grease\"?", "answer": "Simcox", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7bc0b2b316f4693fb678a", "question": "What is a wainwright?", "answer": "A wainwright, also known as cartwright, is someone who repairs wagons and carts.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f46", "question": "Who created the character of Br'er Bear?", "answer": "Joel Chandler Harris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c529877e98cb977789ac", "question": "The Griffith Observatory is located where?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ff", "question": "In the 1890's, what type of cheese did a California man named David Jacks introduce?", "answer": "Monterey Jack", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab183cbaab681b09292188", "question": "Which racing team introduced a six-wheeled race car in 1974 and began racing it in 1976?", "answer": "Tyrrell Racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af94", "question": "Who popularized the Christmas tree in England in the 19th century?", "answer": "Prince Albert", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9b733364247bf200fb86f", "question": "Who wrote \"The Scarlatti Inheritance\"?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a728cb56bcd28c11938328a", "question": "What is the capital of Delaware?", "answer": "Dover", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67e", "question": "How many points must the victor score in a game of cribbage?", "answer": "61 or 121", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c40b", "question": "Where do bumblebees normally nest?", "answer": "Underground", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d3852596a59cbdfbd39b", "question": "What message did the original computer virus display?", "answer": "I'm the creeper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba0c", "question": "What homerun hitter was nicknamed the \"Sultan of Swat\"?", "answer": "Babe Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec234a8dc25ca9e12ef62f", "question": "By what name is \"Calcium oxide\" more commonly known?", "answer": "Quicklime", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf07", "question": "What is campanologist the study of?", "answer": "Bells", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c3b49076251badbead0", "question": "Which First Lady was the first to graduate college?", "answer": "Lucy Hayes -- The wife of President Rutherford B. Hayes, she received her degree from Wesleyan Female College at the age of 18.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a7f5ed6f5f79087132fb41", "question": "Which 1980s wrestling superstar once played baseball in the St. Louis Cardinals' minor league system?", "answer": "\"Macho Man\" Randy Savage", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad30", "question": "What US president endorsed the Louisiana Purchase in 1803?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc6c", "question": "With which team did Brett Favre start his professional football career in 1991?", "answer": "Atlanta Falcons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339804", "question": "What movie soundtrack is Eric Clapton's \"Tears in Heaven\" from?", "answer": "Rush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca9b", "question": "Sophophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Learning or knowledge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b3589615db0d66a186cb54a", "question": "Which popular artist was born as Robyn Fenty in 1988 in Barbados?", "answer": "Rihanna", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6ab2120565ad31a57c824", "question": "Who said, \"He who wishes to serve his country must have not only the power to think, but the will to act\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad9dbe2e748bb36357acdd9", "question": "What is the smallest marine mammal?", "answer": "The Sea otter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c3820815febcc896f927a", "question": "What is the ninth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Sagittarius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ea", "question": "Which Hollywood film studio's logo is a mountain surrounded by 22 stars?", "answer": "Paramount", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42d", "question": "Which is the largest country in Africa by area?", "answer": "Algeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c867", "question": "What is the heaviest chemical element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Uranium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c769", "question": "What word describes the enlargement of bone or tissue at the joint between the big toe and the foot?", "answer": "Bunion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339285", "question": "The alliance \"Chilltown\" consists of what two players?", "answer": "Dr. Will and Mike Boogie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acce", "question": "Who performed \"The Wall\" by the Berlin Wall?", "answer": "Roger Waters", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a95120565ad31a57c801", "question": "Xerxes the Great was the king of what empire?", "answer": "Achaemenid Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990f950fa5fdd6dd25324f6", "question": "What name is given to animals which only eat plants?", "answer": "Herbivores", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600243e54be4723ccac2219d", "question": "\"Leaves of Grass\", first published in 1855, is a poetry collection by which American poet?", "answer": "Walt Whitman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "595245b7736d4be723796b6e", "question": "The tiles used in which game have dots that are called \"Pips\"?", "answer": "Dominoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd3c97e83c707845b2155", "question": "Which electronic musical instrument emits the eeriest of sounds and is the only instrument played without touching it?", "answer": "Theremin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e4", "question": "A skulk is a group of which animals?", "answer": "Foxes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bede", "question": "What is a bellwether?", "answer": "Leader of flock of sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e3", "question": "What \u201cStar Trek\u201d character had a name meaning \u201cfreedom\u201d in Swahili?", "answer": "Uhura", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd3", "question": "What 3 word phrase is written on Martin Luther King's gravestone?", "answer": "Free At Last", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe90a4f01dd7bf43be5e89a", "question": "What is the name for excessive bodily hair growth in women?", "answer": "Hursutism", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b3", "question": "What lake was created when the Bagnell Dam was built across the Osage River?", "answer": "Lake of the Ozarks", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592205d4a4edfd43a087adeb", "question": "Of which country did F.W. de Klerk become president in 1989?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a8", "question": "What nation was led by Rameses the Great?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b66501dd7bf43be5e7db", "question": "What kind of animal is a hellbender?", "answer": "Salamander", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8a", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is O'Shea Jackson?", "answer": "Ice Cube", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e5", "question": "What nationality was writer Arthur C. Clarke?", "answer": "British", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339877", "question": "What planet-destroying device did the Rebels have to destroy in Star Wars?", "answer": "The Death Star", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339227", "question": "What decade did Marty McFly go back to in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1950's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339305", "question": "In the movie \"Gremlins\", what is the name of the little Mogwai given to Billy?", "answer": "Gizmo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f1", "question": "Sleeping Beauty is also known by what other two names?", "answer": "Aurora and Rose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76c58eec85e375820b2d1", "question": "Moraine Lake is found in which National Park?", "answer": "Banff National Park, Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a804", "question": "Omaha, Kansas City, and Sioux City all lie on which river?", "answer": "Missouri River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb3a", "question": "A bridle is a piece of headgear often used to control what animal?", "answer": "A horse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea2", "question": "Who was the first man to swim the English channel?", "answer": "Captain Mathew Webb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c41", "question": "What is Seamus' full name in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Seamus Lavine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c74", "question": "Rupert Giles was the librarian-mentor on what popular TV show?", "answer": "Buffy the Vampire Slayer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea41f9ff048f679a45ab73", "question": "The Astronomical Unit (AU) is a unit of measurement based on the average distance between what two bodies?", "answer": "Earth and the Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b7", "question": "What river was dammed to create the International Amistad Reservoir?", "answer": "Rio Grande River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c5", "question": "Who composed the song \"Rhapsody in Blue\"?", "answer": "George Gershwin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca34", "question": "What geological period followed the Jurassic?", "answer": "Cretaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3d", "question": "How many players are there in a standard quidditch team?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a744", "question": "Yellowstone National Park protects the wilderness of what mountain chain?", "answer": "Rocky Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa2", "question": "What rock epic begins \"The screen door slams, Mary's dress sways\"?", "answer": "Thunder Road", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc57", "question": "What is the literal translation of the dish \"Pad Thai\"?", "answer": "Fried Thai style", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec7", "question": "Which British Sailor and Explorer was killed by Hawaiian natives in 1779?", "answer": "James Cook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdab3320b8cce1e6fda7043", "question": "What common animal is constitutionally protected in Florida?", "answer": "Pigs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdff59f1cf6db9ac4808ceb", "question": "Which U.S. territory is the country\u2019s southernmost point?", "answer": "American Samoa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc17", "question": "What organization was formed to replace \"The League of Nations\"?", "answer": "United Nations", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd823cfd0de9af39e9d46b3", "question": "The first vaccine was invented in what year?", "answer": "1796", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea4531ff048f679a45ab91", "question": "What type of muscle bends a joint in the body?", "answer": "Flexor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd4", "question": "Who killed Count Dooku by cutting off his head?", "answer": "Anakin Skywalker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3913c73aa70ea0b70ad7", "question": "Which settlers added an \"r\" to Arkansas?", "answer": "French (They were told by natives from an Illinois tribe that people in the area now called Arkansas were called \"Akansa\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339984", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what was the name of Barney's snowplowing business?", "answer": "Plow King", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd43a7e83c707845b215a", "question": "What famous actor turned down the role of Trinity in film \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Sandra Bullock turned down the role because she had the understanding that Will Smith was in the film.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d16", "question": "What gangster movie was originally titled \"The Menace\" and eventually subtitled \"The Shame of the Nation\"?", "answer": "Scarface", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592ead5df83302ff91e4647b", "question": "Sophophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Learning", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef62f16ce05a3942286e61", "question": "What was the first song featuring rap to top the Billboard Hot 100?", "answer": "\"Rapture\" by Blondie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e74", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"City Lights\"?", "answer": "Virginia Cherrill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c8d4fbde8045e48466e1", "question": "Why do some plants send chemical signals to bugs?", "answer": "Signal for help -- Leafy tobacco plants send a chemical signal to wasps, who will seek out caterpillars eating the leaves.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a66a", "question": "Jefferson City is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d4", "question": "The Grasshopper cocktail originated from which New Orleans bar?", "answer": "Tujague's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c532", "question": "What two dogs are bred to make a puggle?", "answer": "Pug and beagle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c90d0fa52800b05cac20f10", "question": "What is Eisoptrophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Mirrors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b07", "question": "What is the name of the Wally World mascot in \"National Lampoon's Vacation\"?", "answer": "Marty Moose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394df", "question": "What was the name of the family in \"One Man's Family\" TV show?", "answer": "The Barbours", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f7", "question": "Approximately how many acres is a baseball field?", "answer": "2", "category": "general"}]